<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David J Nevin</title>
    <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on David J Nevin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 David J. Nevin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 21:57:27 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.davidjnevin.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Make a Novel</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/make-a-novel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 14:01:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/make-a-novel/</guid>
      <description>About this course Are you working on a novel or plan to?
The course is open to writers with some writing experience and eager to deepen their writing passion. In eight sessions we cover the key elements of writing long form fiction.
All sessions are online and live with the program coach.
Each session lasts 90-minutes and includes digital handouts, writing exercises and a Q&amp;amp;A time.
Syllabus - What you will learn from this course Week 1: Negotiating with the muse How do napkin scribbles become fully-realised novels?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write Publishable Short Fiction</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/short-story-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 14:01:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/short-story-workshop/</guid>
      <description>About this course In this course aspiring writers will explore and practice ten key elements in writing publishable short fiction.
All ten sessions are online and live with the program coach.
Each session lasts 90-minutes and includes digital handouts, writing exercises and a Q&amp;amp;A time.
Syllabus - What you will learn from this course Week 1: Ideas to Concepts How do initial inspirations become fully-realised short fiction?
Week 2: Character How can we connect our readers with our characters?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Craft Workshops</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 23:54:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/workshops/</guid>
      <description>Workshops All craft workshops and are online and live.
Publishable Short Fiction Start bridging the gap between the stories in your head and your stories on the page.
In this course aspiring writers will discover and practice ten key elements in writing publishable short fiction.
details
Make a Novel We look at managing large projects, developing voice, writing deep true characters, weaving subplots and much more.
The course is open to writers with some writing experience and eager to deepen their writing passion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critique Wheel</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/critique-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 20:48:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/critique-wheel/</guid>
      <description>Critique Wheel The Critique Wheel is a free critique exchange for fiction writers.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to use and designed to handle short fiction in chunks of up to 8,000 words.
The idea is to help writers get useful critique on their works in progress while helping others do the same.
The benefits are many, but in short it&amp;rsquo;s one of the best ways to improve your craft, gain confidence in your voice and get better and better at rewriting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Group</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/writing-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 15:36:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/writing-group/</guid>
      <description>Writing in Good Company We need that quiet time, that space to let our thought coalesce into words and those into sentences.
Writing and moreover improving our writing, I believe, requires a social element too.
There is in the very nature of the art a yearning for external eyes and minds to experience our words and worlds.
To this end I&amp;rsquo;ve founded and organized groups in three different cities so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edit</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/edit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 15:28:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/edit/</guid>
      <description>Under construction </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coach</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/coach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 15:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/coach/</guid>
      <description>Writing it </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/publish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 15:00:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/publish/</guid>
      <description>Publishing I caught the publishing bug way back in secondary school. I helped edit and publish the school magazine for a few issues. It was a joy to play with typesetting and layouts, plus seeing my own and my fellow contributors in print. The sensation of making words somehow more real has stayed with me.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on putting together two books. An anthology of short fiction and a non-fiction work related to the craft of writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critique</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/critique/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 01:41:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/critique/</guid>
      <description>Why exchange critiques? For over seven years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been exchanging critiques and it is the best way to improve your craft.
A good critique has these three characteristics For me, at they very least, a good critique should be objective, generous and actionable.
Objective: While the first may appear obvious, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial for the critiquer to remember this is not a customer is always right scenario. The purpose should be to give the writer an insight into how the piece works in that reader&amp;rsquo;s head and not to get the writer to change something.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>