<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David J Nevin</title>
    <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on David J Nevin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 David J. Nevin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 21:57:27 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.davidjnevin.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vim Commands</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/vim_commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 10:47:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/vim_commands/</guid>
      <description>Too Many Vim Commands Getting back into Vim again and decided this time to take it slower and get the basics well in place before I try and incorporate too many commands. It&amp;rsquo;s the same mentality I&amp;rsquo;m bringing to my Python journey and will reapply to C#. The note below are a mix of my obsidian notes from when I started using Vim in April of 2021 and resources I&amp;rsquo;ve used to better understand the commands this time round.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Search Extended</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/binary_search_extended/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 19:02:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/binary_search_extended/</guid>
      <description>Binary Search Recommended Youtube Playlist Binary searching has been a difficult learning curve for me. It didn&amp;rsquo;t immediately click, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a series of tutorials on youtube. This playlist is excellent.
So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten my head around the binary Search itself, Find Closest NUmber, FInd fixed Point, Find Bitonic Peak, Find First Occurrence.
Later I went through and studied Bisect Method, Square Root and Cyclically Shifted Array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Search</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/binary_search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 23:58:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/binary_search/</guid>
      <description>Binary Search The divide and conquer search method.
Linear Search The sequential searching through all data entries one by until until we find a match.
Time complexity is O(n).
100 101 102 103 104 def linear_search(data, target): for i in range(len(data)): if data[i] == target: return True return False The worst-case runtime of a linear search would be O(n).
Binary Search (Iterative) Note: assumes that the array on which the search will take place is sorted in ascending order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hashing First Steps</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/hashing_first_steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 22:04:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/hashing_first_steps/</guid>
      <description>Tentative steps. Today, I took some first tentative steps into understanding Hash tables:
Fascinating topic, and one I&amp;rsquo;m using at present to complete a Caesar Cipher project. (link to here when complete #TODO)
Here are some excellent resources, I&amp;rsquo;ve found through Engineering with Utsav
Intro to Hash tables
Hashing and chaining
Simple Hash table in Python</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Projects June 19th</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/site_projects_june_19th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 12:41:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/site_projects_june_19th/</guid>
      <description>This post is a culmination of previous project related posts. It&amp;rsquo;s useful for me to see the needs develop and to decide when and what to implement and how I can combine the requirements into clear actions to take.
Sidebar Although I chose the minima theme for it&amp;rsquo;s simplicity, it&amp;rsquo;s purpose was to present a personal writing related site. I wanted and still do want a clean experience for the writing posts and pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Search Tree</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/binary_search_tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 02:08:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/binary_search_tree/</guid>
      <description>Definition A binary search tree (BST) is a tree data structure in which nodes are arranged according to the following property.
The value of the left child of any node will be less than whatever value in that node, and the value of the right child of the node will be greater than the value in that node.
If there aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly two children, the reference to the non-existent child will contain null value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level Order Traversal Binary Tree</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/level_order_traversal_binary_tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 02:08:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/level_order_traversal_binary_tree/</guid>
      <description>Definition Level Order traversal is a breath first transversal. The traversal starts at the root and explores all the nodes at the same depth prior to moving onto the next depth level. A queue is normally needed to capture and keep track of the child nodes encountered bu not yet explored.
A breath-first traversal works well on infinite or cyclical tree, where a depth first traversal might never return with an answer or get lost in the data structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Depth Order Traversals: Binary Tree</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/binary_tree_traversals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 15:10:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/binary_tree_traversals/</guid>
      <description>Tree Traversals (Preorder, Inorder and Postorder) From the root of a binary tree, traverse deeper before going laterally.
Preorder - Node Left Right
Inorder - Left Node Right
Postorder - Left Right Node
Preorder Traversal (nlr) A useful collection type to navigate the nodes traversed is a stack1.
Iteration of Preorder Traversal Push the root to the stack.
Is the stack empty?
Then pop the stack, and record/output the node name/value as visited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Tree Terms</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/binary_tree_terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 23:42:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/binary_tree_terms/</guid>
      <description>Binary Tree Terms A tree has a root and leaves.
A root node has no parent nodes.
A leaf node has zero children.
A lef node is an external node, non leaf node are internal nodes.
The degree of a node is the number of children of that node. The lines between nodes are called edges.
Binary Tree Characteristics In a binary tree, each node has a maximum of two children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Projects - June 17th</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/site_projects_17_06_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 20:57:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/site_projects_17_06_2022/</guid>
      <description>Certificates Section Next mini-project here on this site is to start to put together a list of certificates and courses I&amp;rsquo;ve done. I am loath to do it in html as opposed to some kind of db solution but we&amp;rsquo;ll see.
First I want to get something visible and linkable, as I&amp;rsquo;m unhappy with the LinkedIn certificates section. Too inflexible and not customizable.
It might be as simple as creating new subsection and a matching hugo archetype for certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arrays Educative</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/arrays_educative/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 20:43:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/arrays_educative/</guid>
      <description>Finished the Arrays section I&amp;rsquo;ve been working through the Data Structures and Algorithms course on Educative to develop my python skills.
Learned the two sum problem, optimal task assignment, intersections of two sorted lists, arbitrary precision increment and array advance games solutions.
Fascinating look into the the world of algorithms. Lots more to se of course but really enjoying the progress and the insights.
I also did a quick &amp;ldquo;level test&amp;rdquo; and received a proficiency badge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PlantUML: First Attempts</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/plantuml_first_attempts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 23:06:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/plantuml_first_attempts/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s try out PlantUML PlantUML seems at first glance somewhat similar to Mermaid but with a wider function list.
Following instructions from Paul Dugas I set up a shortcode and added a js file to the assets&amp;gt;static folder.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see:
Hey that worked!
Code:
100 101 102 {{&amp;lt; plantuml id=&amp;#34;example&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} David -&amp;gt; Nevin: J {{&amp;lt; /plantuml &amp;gt;}} The id created a &amp;lt;img id=&amp;quot;plantuml-example&amp;quot;... tag.
Back to linked lists First some experimentation with sequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mermaid: First Attempts</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/mermaid_first_attempts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 09:23:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/mermaid_first_attempts/</guid>
      <description>Mermaid setup. Really basic first effort.
I created a shortcodes folder under my theme layouts folder, adn there created a mermaid.html with the following code.
100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 &amp;lt;script async type=&amp;#34;application/javascript&amp;#34; src=&amp;#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/mermaid/dist/mermaid.min.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt; var config = { startOnLoad:true, theme: &amp;#39;{{ if .Get &amp;#34;theme&amp;#34; }}{{ .Get &amp;#34;theme&amp;#34; }}{{ else }}dark{{ end }}&amp;#39;, align:&amp;#39;{{ if .Get &amp;#34;align&amp;#34; }}{{ .Get &amp;#34;align&amp;#34; }}{{ else }} center{{ end }}&amp;#39; }; mermaid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Section Theme 3</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/hugo_section_theme_003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 22:03:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/hugo_section_theme_003/</guid>
      <description>Okay so that&amp;rsquo;s better. A simpler approach worked. I got playing with a copy of my primary *.html pages in the theme layout folder. I followed the advice to create a subfolder with the same name as my section.
I copied in my files and then altered them there. Also I added a _index.md to my section folder in the content folder.
These tweaks allowed me to alter the site title, adding a link to the section homepage as an additional text in the original title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Section Theme 2 (didn&#39;t work)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/hugo_section_theme_002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 02:16:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/hugo_section_theme_002/</guid>
      <description>Question: If I just copy the template? What happens if I just copy the single.html into the layout/code folder?
This is what happens, which in hindsight makes sense.
I copied over the partial in question and plonked it into the same sub-folder. That didn&amp;rsquo;t work.
I tried copying over the partials, editing the references in the template but without knowing what I&amp;rsquo;m doing I don&amp;rsquo;t know ifI&amp;rsquo;m getting closer or not to a solution or just digging a hole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Section Theme (didn&#39;t work)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/hugo_section_theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:25:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/hugo_section_theme/</guid>
      <description>Hugo Section: A different look and feel. I though that in order to set a different look and feel for a Hugo section, I&amp;rsquo;d create a folder in the current theme layout folder with the same name as the section. In my case that&amp;rsquo;s code.
The theme I&amp;rsquo;m interested in using and adapting is Book or Geekdoc but both require the extened Hugo version. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what that will do to my main site and SASS setup with gulp, so I&amp;rsquo;m steering clear of that for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critique Wheel C#</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/critique_wheel_csharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 21:43:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/critique_wheel_csharp/</guid>
      <description>Raison d&amp;rsquo;être o el porque I built and deployed the Beta version of the critique wheel site in response to a need for the fiction writers in my writing groups to get faster and more actionable critiques on their short stories.
From my Github records, I added the .gitignore on 15 May 2021, so I consider that the start date of the project.
Razor Pages, MySQL The wheel is build on .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Commit</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/first_commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 21:01:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/code/first_commit/</guid>
      <description>Start here As of today, I&amp;rsquo;ve been re-experimenting with programming for 13 months.
This is the first blog post on the topic of my coding experiences. I&amp;rsquo;ve no doubt this layout will develop and mature as I add content.
I hope it serves as a useful resource for anyone that stumbles across it.
This Site This site itself is built using Hugo, a static site generator written in Go. I don&amp;rsquo;t know Go and Hugo doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any deep programming skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Novel</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/make-a-novel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 14:01:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/make-a-novel/</guid>
      <description>About this course Are you working on a novel or plan to?
The course is open to writers with some writing experience and eager to deepen their writing passion. In eight sessions we cover the key elements of writing long form fiction.
All sessions are online and live with the program coach.
Each session lasts 90-minutes and includes digital handouts, writing exercises and a Q&amp;amp;A time.
Syllabus - What you will learn from this course Week 1: Negotiating with the muse How do napkin scribbles become fully-realised novels?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write Publishable Short Fiction</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/short-story-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 14:01:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/short-story-workshop/</guid>
      <description>About this course In this course aspiring writers will explore and practice ten key elements in writing publishable short fiction.
All ten sessions are online and live with the program coach.
Each session lasts 90-minutes and includes digital handouts, writing exercises and a Q&amp;amp;A time.
Syllabus - What you will learn from this course Week 1: Ideas to Concepts How do initial inspirations become fully-realised short fiction?
Week 2: Character How can we connect our readers with our characters?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Craft Workshops</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 23:54:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/workshops/</guid>
      <description>Workshops All craft workshops and are online and live.
Publishable Short Fiction Start bridging the gap between the stories in your head and your stories on the page.
In this course aspiring writers will discover and practice ten key elements in writing publishable short fiction.
details
Make a Novel We look at managing large projects, developing voice, writing deep true characters, weaving subplots and much more.
The course is open to writers with some writing experience and eager to deepen their writing passion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critique Wheel</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/critique-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 20:48:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/notes/critique-wheel/</guid>
      <description>Critique Wheel The Critique Wheel is a free critique exchange for fiction writers.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to use and designed to handle short fiction in chunks of up to 8,000 words.
The idea is to help writers get useful critique on their works in progress while helping others do the same.
The benefits are many, but in short it&amp;rsquo;s one of the best ways to improve your craft, gain confidence in your voice and get better and better at rewriting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Group</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/writing-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 15:36:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/writing-group/</guid>
      <description>Writing in Good Company We need that quiet time, that space to let our thought coalesce into words and those into sentences.
Writing and moreover improving our writing, I believe, requires a social element too.
There is in the very nature of the art a yearning for external eyes and minds to experience our words and worlds.
To this end I&amp;rsquo;ve founded and organized groups in three different cities so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edit</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/edit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 15:28:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/edit/</guid>
      <description>Under construction </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coach</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/coach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 15:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/coach/</guid>
      <description>Writing it </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/publish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 15:00:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/publish/</guid>
      <description>Publishing I caught the publishing bug way back in secondary school. I helped edit and publish the school magazine for a few issues. It was a joy to play with typesetting and layouts, plus seeing my own and my fellow contributors in print. The sensation of making words somehow more real has stayed with me.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on putting together two books. An anthology of short fiction and a non-fiction work related to the craft of writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critique</title>
      <link>https://www.davidjnevin.com/critique/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 01:41:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidjnevin.com/critique/</guid>
      <description>Why exchange critiques? For over seven years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been exchanging critiques and it is the best way to improve your craft.
A good critique has these three characteristics For me, at they very least, a good critique should be objective, generous and actionable.
Objective: While the first may appear obvious, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial for the critiquer to remember this is not a customer is always right scenario. The purpose should be to give the writer an insight into how the piece works in that reader&amp;rsquo;s head and not to get the writer to change something.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>